yes uh good day good morning dear
colleagues first of all I would like to
wholeheartedly thank the management and
top officials of
usim and
uh University for this wonderful
opportunity to deliver a speech at this
wonderful best
university I would like to represent to
you the Contemporary Russian Outlook
insight into the challenges of
globalization
for
Barak probably you have heard about the
Contemporary the nowadays the present
day advisor to President Barack Obama on
geopolitical issues Mr
barana he is representing the American
Outlook into the globalization
challenges
problem but his uh ideas regarding the
globalization and the challenges of
viations are according to our view are
inadequate so actually I will deliver a
lecture regarding this issue I will try
try to develop all
this in our view globalization is an
objective process meaning that
globalization is the concentration of
the productive forces of
humanity we understand that humanity is
single kind is Unified kind and a sing
Spirit
basically we understand that
globalization process as a mean as a as
a as as it is uh related to the
concentration of the productive forces
of the entire human kind is an objective
process and the president of the Russian
Federation used to be speaking all
this
but the control over this process is
subjective is dependent on the
will so what is the current Global
challenge to the entire humankind the
present
day
we will start with a very important
issue in this regard is we will have to
look at the way the change of social
behavior logic took place in the middle
of the 20th
century the whole humankind in
information wise is the two level
system
so the information Exchange in the
humankind in the society has two levels
the one level is that information is
changed at genetical level genetic
level as you can see it on the screen so
the genetic uh the genetic information
change is stable over time it changes
the change of this uh of this process is
the change of the generation
we have analyzed the written history of
humankind and we assess this written
history of humankind uh as deep as 7,000
years
ago we understand that each time the
generation changes one time in 25 years
approximately and that should not be new
to you that the first generation is
delivering new
ideas the second generation is striving
to implement these ideas to bring them
into
life the third generation keeps the
inertia of that press
and the fourth generation overthrows
what has been
done but the society is informatively
changed all also on the social level as
well and the main thing which brings uh
uh brings clue to the process of social
renovation are the
Technologies if you have a deep inside
the historical background say at 5,000
years ago then you could
notice that the world has been unchanged
for many many many Generations over the
last thousand
years which means that technologically
the main uh social and the main
technological branches of the life of
society uh during the life of the same
technologist hundreds or tens and
hundreds of generations went through the
same technological envir
enironment we now live in the 21st
century and it is absolutely common
knowledge to us living in the 21st
century that Technologies change many
form many times over this the lifetime
of one
generation but
if you put these two processes the
biological time and the so-called social
time in
comparison you can see is this as the
lines for rate of information change in
the
society green line is the stable line of
change of information on genetical level
of
humankind the information change on
social level is
variable
if this is objectively so so then the
two lines the green line which is
Constantine and the red line which is
rival going up they should meet at one
certain
point and we were much interested in the
period when these two lines overlapped
with each
other so you can see that the yellow uh
the yellow part of of the scene is
is is exactly marking the period when
the two uh when the two lines glided
when they got into
related and tell you exactly that that
period of time was very dangerous period
of time for the entire
humankind during that time marked as
yellow the two World Wars occurred on
planet
Earth
the the first world war started in
1914 and the second world war started in
1939 that was exactly the period when
the frequency of the two processes were
equal and also as you may remember at
that period of time the whole globe the
whole planet was covered by a wave of
revolutions revolutions were not only in
Russia but took place in China in Mexico
India elsewhere so and it all ended by
the end of the
50s by the end of that period human kind
delivered an atomic
bomb the appearance of the nuclear
weapons and effective uh use of nuclear
weapons as you know from history
displayed to all the humanity
impossibility of waging big Wars with
with the nuclear
weapons so exactly that period which is
marked with yellow here on the screen
was named by us the period of the change
of social behavior
logic that's because if we look into the
period which which is before this period
marked as
yellow we notice one very important
thing that a man living before that
period if that man would acquire some
knowledge could be absolutely confident
that this knowledge will be enough for
his lifetime and even for the lifetime
of his sons daughters and grandsons and
granddaughters that was the period of
the predominance and acquiring of factal
knowledge
and now after that yellow line we we
understand that it is now the third
generation entering life in the New
Logic of social
behavior and even the students of today
they absolutely easily understand that
the factology facts which they are
receiving during the course of Education
become sometimes become obsolete when
they end this
education that is why we are sure that
the new determining factor for the
education of the next generation of this
generation is the methodological educ
it is the predominant
factor in different countries people who
do not see this problem who do not
understand this problem try to solve
that in different
ways say in the United States of America
they try to make the period of Education
more extensive
same about
Russia and uh say education the
secondary education in Russia has
reached 12
years but it is interesting to note that
if the school boys and school girls are
given the methodological grounds for
acquiring new
knowledge
then the process of such education
without losing any quality of
it can be minimized to say seven or
eight
years apart from that what I have told
you you may notice the growing
catastrophic events all over
Earth
the number of social catastrophes and
the number of technogen genetic
catastroph is growing
rapidly we also see it as the the fact
that that people do not understand that
the change of social behavior logic has
already
occurred so what is the the global
Society what is the Contemporary Society
currently we called that Society the mob
Elite
Society we have a definition for the mob
mob is a crowd of of people who live
according to the writings and analyze
things according to some
authorities according to the uh to the
to the authorities of the leaders
according to the authorities of the
sacred writings according to authority
of any other uh Authority in the society
or texts which can be uh which can be
even uh distorted or
misunderstood and we understand that
this mob Elite Society in the current
New Logic of social behavior is not I
cannot leave
out it will
perish
and we understand that in order to to
turn this mob into people we have to
change or dramatically change the
culture so basically this is the key
point for the investigation for the
studies which is being done by a group
of scientists which I'm now here
representing
how what we should do in order to
facilitate that mob becomes
people so I'm now going to briefly
deliver to you some latest studies the
results of these
studies we have identified the so-called
complete function of control of the
social behavior a control full function
cff please pay attention to these
schemes we have identified seven stages
of the complete of the full Control
Function they do objectively exist
whenever a a person wants to take his
own mentality under
control it is definitely applicable to
the control of the social groups
starting with say business starting with
production
yes
even if you look carefully at yourself
at your motivations and behavior you
will see that all these seven functions
are present all the seven factors are
present at uh stage one of this process
you identify the new factor which is
affecting your en
enironment so at this very exact moment
you are solving a task to identify
whether this is new or not new to
you uh the Holy Quran has uh Surah 25
which is called Alan which is in Russian
called the uh uh the determination the
telling we understand that God Allah
gives this determining the uh ability to
tell things according to the
Consciousness and according to the heart
condition and you may already notice
that for some people the new knowledge
is not
existent and others would immediately
identify ah this is new this is new
knowledge on the second stage of the
control full
function you are trying to
the new knowledge into the system of
your stereotypes into the system of your
mental stereotypes which you already
have this is the most difficult task for
you you will have to look into your old
existing
stereotypes and somehow position this
new Factor new information into the
system system of
stereotypes once you have identified
this new factor and you paid attention
to
it then you definitely need that for
something so then you start to create
your own Vector of
goals in regards to this new
Factor
basically the vector of goals is a list
of your
wishes in some decent
order on the first uh place in your
vector of goals you put your goal your
aim which is the last uh to get rid of
if need
be
and the last place is occupied by a goal
which you can easily get rid of when you
solve some other
problems so each of the humans living on
Earth does do does possess some certain
goals what do you do is you Ed your
newly identified vector of goals
regarding new information have received
into your existing Vector of
goals probably you will have to overlook
and oversee and change the hierarchy of
the goals in your vector of
goals and on the fourth stage you create
a con concept for reaching these goals
the fifth stage is more understandable
to use so you create a structure or a
purpose vehicle in order to reach these
goals and Stage six you're just viewing
and contr and uh supervising your
vehicle which you have created specially
to reach that
goals
then at stage seven you either continue
to maintain these vehicles or you
liquidate these vehicles as
needless or if you have reached the
goals which you have set in front of
you so basically these are the seven
stages of full Control
Function they are all always
present if anyone of the stages is
missing is missing regarding your
information which you are putting into
that
stage then it is someone else who is
doing that for
you but then it's not you who
control who control
yourself and and controls that processes
which you want to to keep under your
control but control F function is always
present but you can definitely deliver
more detailed uh picture of each of the
stages
so I would like to ask you one single
question I would like to address to all
of
you can you tell me now the president
the king or the General Secretary of any
country who is controlling the first
four stages of the complete
Control
Function that is not done by the
president of the United
States that is not done by the president
of
Russia that is not done by no
one although there should be someone who
controls the first four stages of the
complete
Control
Function that is why next point is very
important we have to talk about the
kinds of power in the
social we understand that power is the
realized the implemented capability to
control
for you it is very common to understand
that there are three kinds of
Power the legislative
power the executive
power and judicial
power these are common things and you
know uh something which is known
everywhere in the world
World in reality however there are not
three but five kinds of
Power which work all
together and there is in reality there
is no division of powers they work all
as
one
as you remember at stage four of this e
you have to create your own concept of
control so those who control the first
four stages of the complete Control
Function
exist but it is not common knowledge
that it is not really uh something which
is widely discussed you
and the point is not that this kind of
power is hidden away from everybody's
eye you might know that if some process
of some event
exists and there is an image in the
Society of such a process or such an
event but if you do not have the
adequate naming for such an event or
such a
process then this process of this event
is sort of not
existent that's exactly what is
happening now to that kind of power
which we called the conceptual
power Global predictor we called that
conceptual power related to Earth as a
whole the global
predictor control means
prediction and we we know that Napoleon
was the first politician to put that
into these exact
words
when now President Putin was asked once
what gift he would like to have he said
I would like to have the gift of
prediction So This Global conceptual
power was formed according to our ideas
in ancient
Egypt
approximately from 4 to 5,000 years
before
Christ and once having emerged it didn't
go anywhere it did not
vanish conceptual power are the
ideas and
people who are bearing these ideas or
who are capable to adjust these ideas
with
time ancient Egypt was met was
controlled by the 22
heropants herant translated from the
Greek language are the people who know
tomorrow they split it into two teams of
11 11 in the north and 11 in the south
of the
country it was them who created the
procedure the procedure which would as a
result of which we would receive
unanimity and a consens consens
regarding various
issues and not only just by
voting like it is accepted in all the de
democracies of the
world through the use of the same
methodology for the search of Truth
which they
possessed you may ask me why ancient
Egypt
you know that 5,000 years ago only Egypt
was possessing the uh the
historically uh stable written
Culture by analyzing these written
artifacts which refer to the times of
the Jer
far it's approximately 3,000
years
at those time analyzing the situation
they have managed to see the first stage
of the complete function of control they
have identified the new thing which is
the which is now called
globalization they were managed they
managed to understand the globalization
is an objective
process and the control of the
globalization is subjective
process they were the first to uh to go
through the first four stages of the
complete control
function and they have elaborated and
brought about uh the global concept of
control which you know all of you and
everyone of
you and this is the
Bible the Bible is definitely not a
product of mentality of a nedic tribe
called
Jews Bible is a very serious book in
this regard
this the biblical concept or the concept
of the Bible dominates now throughout
the whole
world culture is always uh determined by
the
concept in order to understand the
concept you will have to analyze and
study the culture in which you are
living that is exactly the point where
we we have studed our
research we started to make deep
research of the culture of the X
USSR Western Europe and the United
States of
America this culture is
displayed widely in museums in music in
architecture there are definitely other
cultures like the culture of
Islam theist
orist huist
culture but it is the
Bible which
dominates in the
society
and therefore the Western culture is
aggressively pushing straight forward
throughout the whole
world I visited India once and I
delivering a
lecture in
India I heard I heard an objection from
one of the leaders and he said that look
over the last 200 years there are no
more symbols of any Western culture left
in India
nothing and then I raised a computer and
cell mobile
phone I show them the
Automobiles and I told him that you know
sometimes things speak on a certain
language with with
people and this language is also also
Bor by the biblical
culture this biblical culture gave birth
to the technosphere which we are now
using and whatever we do in order to
defend our
culture you all
know
you all know that the main cultural
center of the western biblical
civilization which is called the
Hollywood it is penetrating all all
parts of the
world may ask why the biblical culture
of the
West has become to dominate in the
society
my answer is that only in the Bible you
can feel you can see the exact exactly
set and straightforwardly
put sociological
Doctrine it sounds like that that and he
is using now the the citing the Bible he
says that you should not give your
brother
silver
bread or
any silver or bread or any other things
that you can give to other nations in
usually
ideas if you give that to us in in in
terms of usury to other peoples then you
will re all over the other
peoples and those peoples who will not
be
who would not like to be your
servants they will be
perished from our Viewpoint this is
direct aggression towards the whole the
entire
humankind and Quran was uh given to
Muhammad in order to stop that
conceptual aggression in the world
we think that there were three
Revelations first revelation was given
on the very upside of the mop Elite
pyramid to the
pH to the 10th Faron of the 18th Dynasty
13th century before
Christ that far broke all ties with the
uh
withan of
am and he was the first to raise the
issue of one single
God and he was putting this into these
verses of the him and of
Aton but the uh the priest hierarchy put
this undercover put this Anem
undercover and the world knew about
learned about this Anon only at the end
of 19th
century next Revelation was given to is
to to to the
Christ knew he was literate man he knew
writing he he could
read but he didn't not put the
Revelation on
paper so he went to the people with just
verbal
prophesies
he definitely knew that his teaching
will be uh further uh perverted
by Third Revelation was given to
Muhammad in
Russia we have many
people who study all the three
Revelations
we have compared the of Aton which is
13th century
BC the contents of Quran which is
seventh
century these two Revelations are
divided by 2,000
years we have applied some computer
Technologies in order to make
comparative assessment of what what is
exactly the contents
about when we have done that we were
amazed and astonished not only by the uh
Unity of the
contents but also the text and the the
frequency and the rhythmic of these
Revelations uh we call it the white
poetry so it's uh in Russian it's called
White poet we have the white poetic
effect present in both these
Revelations and the fact which we see
now is the standoff between the world of
Islam and the world of
Bible is the result that in Quran you
have an absolutely fixed right
definition of
usury and this is an absolutely directly
fixed negative approach to
usury from that I should say that there
is quranic quranic
Islam and we understand that it is the
historic Ally set
Islam find difference between quranic
Islam and historically set
Islam the point is that Muslims all over
the world cannot
unite and divided themselves into shs
and
sunnit there is no saying in Quran about
that
similar similar thing absolutely similar
thing is with
Christianity the historically set
Christianity and the teaching of Isa the
teaching of
Christ are far far far away from each
other was long away
from I'm sorry to make this uh hisorical
backgrounds delivering to
you but I am convinced that I'm talking
to the high level of
audience and I would like you to
understand in Russia there is definitely
some some understanding of the religious
uh faiths and religious uh beliefs by
far more more
advanced the historically said religion
the the teachings themselves are
different in a ways similar
to similar to the fact how they decorate
an icon in Russia from the icon itself
so make they make these gold decorations
covering almost all kinds of icons and
that the icon itself is not visible
sometimes we uh we actually uh make
difference between trust to God and
trust in
God and this is sort of uh giving you
guidance further how trust in God
differs from trust to God
so the whole humankind is now on the
edge of overcoming the real
atheism and we have atheism of the two
times as we
see the soal idealistic
atheism and materialistic atheism
in Russia over 1,000 years we have been
overcoming the idealistic
atheism idealistic atheism of all the
churches named after
Christ also in Russia we had three
generations of overcoming the
materialist atheism of
marxist
basically the point of Russia is that
Russia in some in this regard is by far
and more advanced than other countries
they have experienced a
lot to put it in plain terms the the
idealistic atheists say God exists but
they they make some presumptions about
God which is is not inherent to God and
that's why they they
atheists sometimes in Russia they will
say that God is is a grandfather with a
beard or something like
that that Jesus Christ is the Son of
God although Quran speaks absolutely
right on this
point that God Allah doesn't have no
children no
helpers
materialists material atheists are
absolutely simple they say okay there is
no God at
all when you ask this material atheist
what is exist in there they would said
okay nature exists and some laws
exists and basically what they do they
make they give the tra of God to the
God's
creation Quran says this that
presumption does not cannot deprive you
from the
truth I'm getting back to the to to my
lecture
again those who represent this
conceptual power know that in very great
detail
is they make the collision between the
two different types of this atheism they
use they make these collisions between
the the many times of
atheism so basically the Islamic Terror
is the result of such collisions because
it's different understanding of the true
Islamic and quranic Islam and the
historical this is also an aggression
against Islam so the so-called Islamic
terrorism is a sort of biblical
aggression
towards so there are five kinds of
Power
you already know something about the
true nature of the conceptual
power its main uh tra of character is
that this kind of power is autocreated
by its nature and it disregards all
Democratic
procedures you cannot be elected to the
conceptual
power you cannot definitely pay the bill
and get elected to the
conceptual and you cannot be there by a
recommendation of some high level
authorities
it's uh actually one point is that the
current mop Elite Society is run under
the formula that each individual Works
to the measure of understanding things
for himself and for the measure of non
understanding things he works for
someone who understands more so
basically the true thing is that you can
be there in the conceptual Power by the
measure of your understanding of
things
so conceptual power is the highest intas
Social Power which is their
existent conceptual power affects uh
superstate
control according to the formula which
was once mentioned by plutar who said
that you control but you as well being
controlled conceptual power brings about
the concept for the whole
man
even when this concept is anti-human by
its nature and they have to think how to
put this concept into acceptable terms
for the public mentality then they would
need some ideologies to wrap this
concept into
applicable terminology so the second
kind of power is ideological
power and then we come down to the kinds
of Power which we all already know is
legislative number three
what they do is basically based on the
concept they based on the concept and
based on the current ideology they
create
laws and then comes executive or
administrative power and executive power
implements these laws by the use of
various uh leverages they they
us and finally we come down to judicial
power which its main goal is to defend
the ruling the dominating concept
against interference of other
Concepts I would like to say that in
Russia currently nowadays we have we
have the alternative concept to the
existing biblical
concept it is uncovers and unveils all
the necessary information and
knowledge we called that ladies and
gentlemen can you please put your hand
together and welcome
professorin
first of all I would like to thank
esteemed
Mr for making such wonderful meeting and
meeting you
that is true four months ago we had very
very important and very informative
meeting with
Mr it considered the current situation
of the Islam Islam
world
we also spoke about the differences
between the historical Islam and the
real true quranic
Islam I could definitely deliver a very
extended speech or lecture in this
regard to theed
audience on the view of the Russian
Russian view towards the future of
and from this lecture you could very
easily understand that the problems of
the so-called Islamic terrorism do not
have any respect to the true quranic
Islam
nevertheless we all will witness huge
big problems in the next 20 30 years to
come those problems will arise from the
differences from huge differences
between the historic Islam as we see it
and quranic
Islam
today my my lecture today I would like
to dedicate with your commission to the
issues of
globalization it's various views towards
globalization and some uh some
alternative view which is now in
Russia
President Obama the US president
President Obama now has an advisor on
globalization his name is Barak Han and
probably you have viewed his delivery of
American style
globalization
recently this is exactly the last minute
understanding of the United States by
the United States establishment of the
globalization of the meanings of the
globalization and we had done a very
thorough study of what is there in the
minds of the American analytical think
tanks and I want to provide you to
present to you the alternative vision of
globalization
and also my point is to give you to try
to give you the alternative uh thesises
the alternative ideas which are
absolutely closed to the understanding
of the American
mentality that is the meaning which
stands behind the theme for our meeting
today which called which is called the
Russian response to contemporary
challenges of
globalization first of all I would like
to say that in our understanding
globalization is an objectively run
objective
process and several years ago our
president Mr Vladimir Putin spoke on
this and confirmed that this is an
objective
process objective process in he implied
that this is an objective process of
integration of the productive forces of
the humankind of the entire
Humanity
but however it appears to be with
globalization being the objective
process the concept of control of
globalization is purely subjective is
dependent to the
will that is why you can see that in
some in someone's interests the tension
between globalists and anti-globalists
is carefully caressed and and and made
made public to everyone's
eye globalization didn't start in the
20th century or 21st century it exists
for long as as long as the world global
historical process
existed
we were able to look deep into the
history of this process for
approximately 7,000 years
back we are using the uh written
artifacts for analyzing this
verses the scripts of anient Egypt
Babylon
Assyria and other AR
so what is what is the true challenge of
the Contemporary globalization process
what is it how can
specify I will try to explain it to you
and present it over this scheme which
you can
see
imagine that you're living 3 or 4,000
years
ago you see the world technologically
almost unchanged and technologically
unadvanced you can see the dozens or
even hundreds of generations of
humankind lived through the period of
the same
Technologies
years passed the GES pass and
generations passed but the world was
left absolutely Tech technically the
same as it used to
be while many of us present here in this
call live at the ends of the 20th
century and the beginning of the 21st
Century
and you can witness yourselves see for
your own with your own eyes that during
the life of one generation Technologies
has changed many
times in the main branches of social
life technology has changed from five to
six times during the time period of one
generation
what has happened what has uh what has
really happened in the middle of the
20th century let's look at
it I want you to pay your most attention
to this period of
time
time can be different you can speak of
historical time of social time of
biological
time or even astronomic
time everything is dependent on which
exact process you take as ealon
as
so here on this on this SCH you can see
the two processes green is the
biological fluctuation
process its frequency is the same over
all the period of
time and you can see the social
fluctuation process with variable
fluctuation
frequency
and actually we dis close discovered the
fact that these two processes were never
being considered
together humankind is the information
system comprised of the two levels as we
think generically you can you can see
the information uh Innovation through
the impacts of the genetic
codes on the social level we we see the
change of Technologies as the
information change which goes through
penetrates deeper the
society that's why we can speak about
the rate or the pace of change of the
information situation both genetically
and socially and you can see these two
lines on the
bottom so you can see that the rate of
renewal of the information on genetic
level is the
same and you can see it's different on
the social or out out the genetic level
level of
information that definitely you canate
that sooner or later these rats will be
meeting somewhere these two lines will
be meeting at one definite
point so we have gone through that
period we now past that period it has
been a very dangerous period for the
whole
humankind
and this period of time actually was
during the middle U Middle years of the
20th
century during that period of time the
world has witnessed two
world that was the period of huge Global
political arrest and social
revolutions
by the end of that period world has
witnessed Atomic nuclear
weapons which actually which actually
put an end to the accessibility or
usability of world wars which we had
witnessed in 20th
century time basically in scientific
terms we're speaking of the fact that
the new the change of the ethalon
fluctuation rates of Social and
biological time has
occurred which finalized which was
finalized by the end of the 20th
century so basically the world The World
At Large and we together we are living
in a totally different Epoch a totally
different
time the ancient priests knew about the
such a period of time in the human
history and they called that apocalypsis
as a Biblical
ter
so what does it mean what does this
comparison of the rates mean what
traditions
mean it appeared that these lines are
determining the social behavior
Logic on the
whole this is also an objective event
and it doesn't really matter only in
Russia but it is definitely going
throughout the whole
world so before the middle of the 20th
century we had one logic of social
behavior we've seen that
logic starting from the middle of the
20th century there was totally different
logic of social
behavior
to my deep regret all the leaders of all
the world of all the
countries do not know about
that but you can definitely feel it or
perceive it through a visible
catastrophic events which are going on
or spreading throughout the whole
world the number of catastrophic events
is
growing
one of the main reasons for that is that
the society is not adequate adequately
deceiving this historical change which
has occurred in the social norms of
behavior of
humanity so what is the main essence of
such a dramatic
change you will easily understand
that
if someone from you before the middle of
the 20th centuries would receive some
education get educated at that
times that that education would be that
knowledge you received would be enough
and sufficient not only for your life
but for your life of your children and
grandchildren
what really mattered at those times was
the factology the number of facts which
you can operate and
proceed starting from the middle of the
20th
century there is no more stable
factology factology is becoming obs lead
NE within five or six years so you have
to revew your
knowledge and what will be determining
the future of humanity is ability to go
to methodology of new knowledge of
getting new
knowledge
this event which I have just told about
was open this is closed in
Russia definitely we have to go further
and we made uh made some delivery some
research work inside the methodology of
getting new adequate
knowledge this me ology is called in
Russia the adequate adequately uh
complete theory of
control inside this adequately complete
uh uh control theory the core thing is
the
control uh control fun function complete
function of control
cff so and you can understand that CF
describes circulation of Information
Society and control starting from the
setting Vector of goals to completion of
control so it can be splitted into seven
stages of
control even if you look at the events
of your life of your everyday life you
will definitely see each one of these
seven uh seven
points they are there when you're using
selfcontrol when you're using
controlling your own
psychology these uh seven seven
principles can also be applied to any uh
object control like the society itself
of the world
L each time when your intellect meets
something new it it uh it really is
under the pressure of getting
understanding this what is new what is
there how can you even know what is new
whether this is new to your mentality
and to your knowledge or this is an old
thing how can you tell what is new or
what is
old you're just your your brain your
mentality is just solving the task of
whether this is it or this is not
it and definitely at this point your new
knowledge is not there embedded into the
into the system of your stereotypes
which you have
so each individual intellect creates
huge work elaborates hardly over trying
to identify what kind of this what kind
of stereotypes could be appli to this
novel which you're which
are
I could definitely deliver a very well a
big lecture regarding each of the
individual stages of the Control
Function but because of lack of time I
will just say few words
this then if you have identified this
new information new factor and you have
put it into into the framework of your
stereotypes then the next stage is you
will definitely go and ask yourself what
is the purpose what I want to do with
that what is the target of what are my
goals about this new
situation so the fourth stage which you
definitely follow but you never think
about this this is done almost
automatically for you by your intellect
is that you are forming concept of
control over this new
situation the other things are
absolutely easily understandable so
you're making a structure or you're
making a vehicle which will bring you to
the
goal then you supervise whether the
structure is operating properly whether
it the structure is really instrumental
to meet your
needs
and then at stage seven if the structure
has completed the goal which you have
identified then you just liquidate the
structure or reform the
structure but I would like to ask you